Guide to the Norman D. Anderson Collection on Ferris Wheels and Related Materials
Norman D. Anderson Collection on Ferris Wheels and Related Materials
- Publications
  - Amusement Park Journals, 1916-1970
    - Newsletters
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 150 [newsletter, pdf], 2012
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 151 [newsletter, pdf], 2012
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 152 [newsletter, pdf], 2012; 2012 2012
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 153 [newsletter, pdf], 2012; 2012 2012
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 154 [newsletter, pdf], 2013; 2013 2013
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 155 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
        152.14.136.62:\preservation\MC00432\prelimContainer\Accession_no_2013_0015\ferriswheelnewsletter_155_2013.pdf
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 156 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
        152.14.136.62:\preservation\MC00432\prelimContainer\Accession_no_2013_0025\ferriswheelnewsletter_156_2013.pdf
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 157 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
        152.14.136.62:\preservation\MC00432\prelimContainer\Accession_no_2013_0043\ferriswheelnewsletter_157_2013.pdf
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 158 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
        152.14.136.62:\preservation\MC00432\prelimContainer\Accession_no_2013_0061\
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 159 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
        152.14.136.62:\preservation\MC00432\prelimContainer\Accession_no_2013_0093\
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 160 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
        152.14.136.62:\preservation\MC00432\prelimContainer\Accession_no_2013_0173\
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 161 [newsletter, docx], 2013
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 162 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 163 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 164 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 165 [newsletter, PDF], 2013
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 166 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 167 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 168 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 169 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 170 [newsletter, docx], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 171 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 172 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 173 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 174 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
      - Ferris Wheel News, No. 175 [newsletter, PDF], 2014
  - Paul Braithwaite Publications
    These publications focus on the subject of patents. They also provide useful information on several different kinds of amusement rides.
    - Arcades and Slot Machines, with A-Z of British Manufacturers 1870-1970, 1997 (Legalbox 30, Folder 9)
    - Swings: Swings, Park Swings, Overboats, Over the Tops, 1996 (Legalbox 30, Folder 9)
    - Handlists, Handbooks, and Index to Thomas Frost's "The Old Showmen and the Old London Fairs", 1980s-1990s (Legalbox 30, Folder 10)
    - John Carter's Jubilee Steam Gallopers, A Bibliography on Fairs, and Booklets related to Roundabout Patents, 1988-1995 (Legalbox 30, Folder 11)
    - Overboats and British Amusement Ride Patents, 1993 and 1995 (Legalbox 30, Folder 12)
  - Industrial and Company Publications
    - Eli Bridge Company Publications, including Allan Herschell and the Towanda Machine: An Exhibiton Catalogue by Diane Raines, 1893-2000 (Legalbox 30, Folder 13)
    - W.F. Mangels Carousel Works, Catalogue No. 3, 1880 (Legalbox 30, Folder 15)
  - Ephemeral Publications
    These publications include a book of patents, the publications of Yuko Fukui (which includes a Japanese children's book on Ferris wheels), the draft of a historical fiction novel, an original, unpublished Senior Engineering thesis from Cornell University (dated 1894), and several other publications which are geared towards tourists and entertainment.
    - Cut and Assemble a Ferris Wheel, 1992 (Legalbox 30, Folder 16)
    - United States Patents filed by Edward Huber or assigned to Edward Huber or the Huber Manufacturing Company, 1870-1910 (Legalbox 30, Folder 14)
    - Small Books on Central Park and the Philadelphia Toboggan Company, undated (Legalbox 30, Folder 17)
    - Anthony J. Hartmann Novel, Draft (Legalbox 31, Folder 5-6)
    - Yuko Fukui, A History of Ferris Wheels (booklet), 2011 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Yuko Fukui, "Ferris Wheels Around the World", Takusan-no Fushigi, no. 301 (January 2011) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Yuko Fukui, Ferris Wheels Around the World: Illustrations (Mika Tanaka, artist), 2010 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Yuko Fukui, Ferris Wheels Around the World: transcription from Japanese (preliminary translation), 2011 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Yuko Fukui, Ferris Wheels Around the World: Article from Ferris Wheel Newsletter, no. 127, 2011 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Thesis. Test of Power Plant of Ferris Wheel by Paul Messer - J.S. Goddard, 1894; 1894 1894 (Halfbox 12)
- Research Files of Norman D. Anderson
  This series contains the research of Dr. Norman Anderson, pertaining to Ferris wheels and other aspects of the amusement business. The media included spans a wide variety of formats and covers a large time frame. Though the research material is dated from the nineteenth century, most of the documents are reproductions garnered from Anderson's prolific research. Dr. Anderson kindly included a preliminary finding aid to the collection for those who would like a more in-depth introduction to the materials. Arranged in subseries as organized by Anderson.
  - Inventory of Collection Created by Norman Anderson
    - Ferris Wheel Archives, December 2011 Revision and other materials (Box 6, Folder 4)
      This document provides an itemized list of the first 418 items in Anderson's research collection, as well as useful information on the materials. Recommended to researchers.
  - Columbian Exposition, Chicago (CEC) Research Files
    The Columbian Exposition in Chicago, also known as the Chicago World's Fair, was held in Chicago, Illinois in 1893. The material in this subseries represents a vast amount of research conducted by Dr. Anderson regarding the fair. Documents are listed in order according to Anderson's numbering system.
    - Columbian Exposition in Chicago- 26-50, 1890s-1980s (Legalbox 7, Folder 2)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) - 51-75: Columbian Exposition/St. Louis Exposition/George Ferris, 1900s (Legalbox 7, Folder 3)
    - Columbian Exposition in Chicago (CEC) - 76-100, 1900s (Legalbox 7, Folder 4)
    - Columbian Exposition in Chicago (CEC) 101-125, 1800s-1900s (with some earlier information) (Legalbox 7, Folder 5)
      This folder includes reproduced informative material and correspondence from a vast range of dates. Though primarily contains information from the 19th and 20th centuries, it also includes earlier information,including a photocopy of A Memoir of Sylvanus Ferris 1773-1861, published by his descendant, Charles Ferris Getteny, in 1935. It also includes a photocopy ofCar No. A Romance of the Ferris Wheel, The Narrative of James Black (original dated 1893).
    - Columbian Exposition in Chicago (CEC) 126-150, 1890s-1980s (Legalbox 7, Folder 6)
    - Columbian Expositon Chicago 151-175, 1890s-1980s (Legalbox 7, Folder 7)
      This folder includes a photocopied editiorial cartoon regarding the "Desperate Case" of Forest Park in St. Louis and copies of newspaper articles regarding exhibitions, in addition to other materials.
    - Colmbian Exposition Chicago 176-200, 1890s-1980s (Legalbox 7, Folder 8)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) 201-225, 1900s-1990s (Legalbox 8, Folder 1)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) 226-250, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 8, Folder 3)
      Includes American Scientist, May-June 1993 andMechanical Engineering, June 1993, in addition to other articles.
    - Columbian Expositon Chicago (CEC) 251-275, InterOcean, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 8, Folder 4)
    - InterOcean, Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) 276-299, 1890s (Legalbox 8, Folder 5)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago 302-325, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 8, Folder 6)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) 326-350 Schmitz Material, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 8, Folder 7)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) 351-375, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 9, Folder 1)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) 376-400, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 9, Folder 2)
      Includes a photocopy from American Girl magazine, a publication by the Girl Scouts of America.
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago (CEC) 401-418: Additional Material to be Submitted Later NDA 12/13/2011, 1890s-200s (Legalbox 9, Folder 3)
      Photocopies from World's Fair "Puck" magazine, as well as correspondence relating to research and information on steel and iron manufacturing
    - Columbian Exposition in Chicago (CEC)-1, 1890s-1980s (Legalbox 7, Folder 1)
    - Columbian Exposition Chicago, artifacts, 1900s (Halfbox 33, Folder 1-2)
      Includes a souvenir booklet and a color-illustrated publication produced by The Chicago Tribune.
  - Ferris Wheel Material by State, Exhibiton, or Related Individual, 1900s (Legalbox 14, Folder 1)
    - Material Categorized by Related Individual or Company
      - Braithwhite, Paul folder (1 of 2), 1989-1995 (Legalbox 23, Folder 9)
        This material primarily concerns Anderson's Ferris Wheels: An Illustrated History and information on the London Eye.
      - Braithwhite, Paul folder (2 of 2), 1989-1995 (Legalbox 23, Folder 10)
      - Brill, (A.K.)-Peoria, (Illinois)-Hewitt, 1949, 1976 (Legalbox 15, Folder 6)
        A.K. Brill was 20th century builder and showman.
      - Chance Meeting Company, 1980s-1990s (Legalbox 16, Folder 7)
        Contains material pertaining to Chance amusement ride manufacturing company.
      - Chew, Mike, 1900s, mostly post-1950 (Legalbox 13, Folder 9)
        This research file contains information accquired from and correspondence with Mike Chew.
      - Conderman,William; Hornell, New York (Legalbox 19, Folder 1-4)
      - Dahlinger, Fred; The Fred Dahlinger, Jr. Papers, Folder (1 of 3), 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 20, Folder 16)
      - Dahlinger, Fred; The Fred Dahlinger, Jr. Papers, Folder (2 of 3), 1880s-1990s (Legalbox 20, Folder 17)
      - Dahlinger, Fred; The Fred Dahlinger, Jr. Papers. Folder (3 of 3), 1880s-1990s (Legalbox 21, Folder 1)
      - Dahlinger Materials, 1994, some from Fred Fried Archives (Legalbox 31, Folder 1-4)
        Most of this material is interesting from a historical and artifactual perspective. While much of the material is photographic, booklets, ticket stubs, and other ephemera is included. This includes two covers from Osteopathic Magazine, circa 1930s. There are also several pieces related to the Risenrad Ferris Wheel in Vienna, Austria at the Prater.
      - Daily Inter Ocean and Other Chicago Papers (1 of 2), 1800's (Legalbox 26, Folder 11)
      - Daily Inter Ocean and Other Chicago Papers (2 of 2), 1800's (Legalbox 26, Folder 12)
      - Eli Bridge Company Files, 1-25, 1900's (Legalbox 15, Folder 3)
      - Eli Bridge Company Files, 25-50, 1912-1977 (Legalbox 15, Folder 4)
        Includes memorial booklet for W.E. Sullivan (1861-1932), The Optimist, October 1916 and Big Eli: The Men and their Ferris Wheels.
      - Eli Bridge Company Files, 50-100, 1900's mostly after 1950 (Legalbox 14, Folder 9)
        Includes Big Eli Wheel Parts List (1983), price lists, and a publication of "Big Eli: The Men and their Ferris Wheels," along with other material related to the Eli Bridge Company and their Ferris Wheels.
      - Eli Bridge Company catalogs, etc. (1 of 3), 1980s (Legalbox 14, Folder 10)
        In addition to related articles, this file contanis: a big Eli Pricing guide, Eli Bridge Company Operation and Maintenance of Big Eli Wheels guide, Eli Bridge Company Wheel ads, product diagrams and photos from 1985, Instructions for Erecting and Operating Big Eli Wheels, and other related publications.
      - Eli Bridge Company catalogs, etc. (2 of 3), 1980s (Legalbox 15, Folder 1)
      - Eli Bridge Company catalogs, etc. (3 of 3), 1992-2000 (Legalbox 15, Folder 2)
      - Eli Bridge Company: A Century of Wheels, 1893-1993 (Legalbox 15, Folder 5)
      - Fried, Frederick "Fred", 1980-1990s (Legalbox 19, Folder 5)
      - Fukui, Yuko (1 of 3), 1980s-1990s (Legalbox 25, Folder 5)
        Various materials sent by Yuko Fukui to Norman Anderson, including collectible pins from Japan's Wonder Wheel and a copy of 19th century piano sheet music entitled, "An Afternoon in Midway Plaisance." This folder consists mostly of correspondence between Fukui and Anderson concerning Ferris wheels. The focus is on Japanese Ferris wheels.
      - Fukui, Yuko (2 of 3), 1980s-1990s (Legalbox 25, Folder 6)
      - Fukui Yuko, (3 of 3), 1980s-1990s (Flatbox 32)
      - Graydon, James Weir; Large European Ferris Wheel, 1890s-2000s (Legalbox 24, Folder 5)
      - Klasey, Jack Folder (1 of 3), 1890s-1900s (Legalbox 15, Folder 7)
        Includes Floppy Disks with Tiff files.
      - Klasey, Jack Folder (2 of 3) (includes 2 3.5 in disks), 1890s-1900s (Legalbox 15, Folder 8)
      - Klasey, Jack Folder (3 of 3), 1890's-1900's (Legalbox 15, Folder 9)
      - Quincy Stubbs; Waterloo, Iowa, 1900-2008 (Legalbox 16, Folder 4)
        This folder contains research from the 1990s and early 2000s, with information primarily pertaining to the early to mid 1900s.
      - Harris Papers and Correspondence, Minnesota, 1900s (Legalbox 16, Folder 16)
        Includes account of seeing Halley's comet in 1910, xerox copy of St. Louis World's Fair fairground map, and correspondence with Eleanor Harris.
      - Herschell-Spillman, early 1900s, 1980s (Legalbox 18, Folder 10)
        Contains material related to the Herschell-Spillman Carousel Company that emerged in the early 1900s.
      - Isleib, Charles E., 1900s-2000s (Legalbox 18, Folder 1)
        Information pertaining to Charles E. Islieb, a Ferris Wheel builder and operator. Most of the material relates to the early 20th century.
      - Jamestown Expositon (Legalbox 21, Folder 3)
      - Parker, Charles Wallace, 1920s-1980s (Legalbox 16, Folder 6)
        All information contained in this file pertains to C.W. Parker, popularly known as the "Carnival King."
      - Weingardt, Richard, 2000s (Legalbox 13, Folder 11)
        Research, material, and correspondence relating to Richard Weingardt.
      - Westerdale, Robert; Robert Westerdale Papers, circa 1970s (Legalbox 21, Folder 8)
      - People, Miscellaneous, circa 1910s-1960s (Legalbox 22, Folder 2)
      - Amusement Business (clippings), 1960's (Legalbox 28, Folder 2)
    - Material Categorized by Exhibition
      - Aeroscape 1915 Exhibition, circa 1915 (Legalbox 13, Folder 5)
      - Columbian Exposition Chicago- Additional Materials, 1890s-1900s (Legalbox 16, Folder 1)
    - Material Categorized by Amusement Ride
      - Buffalo Aerio-Cycle, 1900s (Legalbox 18, Folder 8)
        Though most of the material related to the Aerio-Cycle dates to the early 1900s, there is a range of research material in this file dating from the early 1900s to later in the 20th century.
      - Chubbuck Wheel Swing, circa 1900-1910, 1980s (Legalbox 18, Folder 9)
        No Subnote Content
      - Dare Wheel, 1870s and 1980s (Legalbox 18, Folder 3)
        Charles W.P. Dare was a bulider of wooden Ferris Wheels in the 1870s. This folder includes photocopied material from that era, as well as correspondence from the 1980s pertaining to the Dare Wheel.
      - Firth Wheel, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 13, Folder 6)
        The material included after the folder was originally stored in the folder by Dr. Anderson, but removed due to preservation concerns. Includes information pertaining to the death and remembrance of historian, Ray Clary.
      - Flip-Flop (carnival ride), 1903-1908 (Legalbox 24, Folder 1)
      - London Eye, 1997-2007 (Legalbox 24, Folder 3)
      - New York Clipper, 1890-1906 (Legalbox 18, Folder 5)
      - Stroble Ferris wheel, (Ohio), 1980s (Legalbox 19, Folder 7)
        Material pertains to Stroble Manufacturing Company of Marion, Ohio (circa early 1900s).
      - Swooper, 1920s (Legalbox 16, Folder 17)
      - Unbuilt Wheels and Towers, 1850s-2000s (Legalbox 26, Folder 5-8)
      - Velares-Stay Wheel, 1941-2008 (Legalbox 13, Folder 8)
    - Material Categorized by State
      - Additional State-Related Materials, (primarily Tennessee, with some information from Texas and Ohio), 1990s and May 1940 (Legalbox 20, Folder 9)
      - Alabama, 1965 (Legalbox 13, Folder 1)
      - Alaska, 1961 and undated (Legalbox 13, Folder 2)
      - Arizona, Phoenix; Including Phoenix Iron Works, 1980s (Legalbox 19, Folder 10-11)
      - Arkansas (Legalbox 13, Folder 3)
        Includes photograph from Arkansas Department of Parks and Tourism of a Ferris Wheel at Magic Springs Family Fun Park.
      - Atlanta, Phoenix and Early Wheels (Legalbox 14, Folder 5)
      - California, General (Legalbox 13, Folder 4)
      - California, Long [Beach?], 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 13, Folder 7)
      - Colorado (Legalbox 13, Folder 10)
      - Connecticut, 1840s-1990s (Legalbox 13, Folder 12)
      - District of Columbia, including Smithsonian (Legalbox 14, Folder 1-2)
      - Georgia (Legalbox 14, Folder 4)
      - Hawaii, 1980s-2000s (Legalbox 14, Folder 6)
      - Idaho, 2005 (Legalbox 14, Folder 7)
      - Illinois (Legalbox 14, Folder 8)
      - Indiana, 1934-2007 (Legalbox 16, Folder 2)
      - Iowa, 1860-1999 (Legalbox 16, Folder 3)
      - Kansas, 1916-1990s (Legalbox 16, Folder 5)
      - Kentucky, 1923-1990s (Legalbox 16, Folder 8)
        Includes an article on a minority park in Kentucky entitled "Park Season for Negroes." The article is dated July 21, 1923.
      - Louisiana, 1938 (Legalbox 16, Folder 9)
      - Maine, 1994 (Legalbox 16, Folder 13)
      - Maryland, 1970s and 1992 (Legalbox 16, Folder 10)
      - Revere Beach, Massachusetts, 1880s-1980s (Legalbox 16, Folder 12)
      - Michigan, 1916-1980s (Legalbox 16, Folder 11)
      - Michigan, 1906-2000s (Legalbox 16, Folder 14)
      - Minnesota, 1920s-1990s (Legalbox 16, Folder 15)
        In addition to varied material relating to amusements in Minnesota, including Knott's Camp Snoopy, this file contains a reproduction copy of a photograph from the 1937 Minnesota State Fair and an original color booklet on the Swooper ride from the late 1920s, featuring extensive illustrations. Between the 1937 photograph and the Swooper booklet was originally placed the folder on the Harris papers, which has since been moved into a subsequent file for preservation purposes.
      - Missouri, 1900s (Legalbox 17, Folder 1)
      - Mississippi, 1911,1955, and 1989 (Legalbox 17, Folder 2)
      - Montana, 1900s-2000 (Legalbox 17, Folder 3)
      - Nebraska; Northeast Omaha, 1898, trans. Mississippi, 1898-1990s (Legalbox 17, Folder 5)
      - New Jersey, 1920s-1990s (Legalbox 17, Folder 7)
        Includes a 1920s era color brochure for Bertrand Island Park on Lake Hopatcong, New Jersey with graphics.
      - Asbury Park, New Jersey, 1895 (Legalbox 17, Folder 8)
      - Alantic City, New Jersey Ferris Wheel (Legalbox 17, Folder 9)
      - New Mexico, 1930s-1970s (Legalbox 17, Folder 4)
      - New York City (Legalbox 18, Folder 4)
      - New York, Coney Island; including Coney Island Ferrris Wheel (Legalbox 18, Folder 6-7)
        Also includes a copy of an article on Coney Island's Museum from the Scientific American, June 1930.
      - New York State, 1850s-1990s (Legalbox 18, Folder 2)
      - Nevada, 1960s-2002 (Legalbox 17, Folder 6)
      - Ohio, 1900s, spans 20th century (Legalbox 19, Folder 6)
      - Oklahoma, 1910-1993 (Legalbox 19, Folder 8)
      - Oregon, undated (Legalbox 19, Folder 9)
      - Pennsylvania, 1940s-1990s (Legalbox 19, Folder 12)
        The dates in this file range throughout the 1900s, with some information garnered in the 2000s, though this information was gathered at that date and the information it contains is dated earlier.
      - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, 1876 (Legalbox 26, Folder 9)
      - Rhode Island, General, 2000 (Legalbox 20, Folder 1)
      - Rhode Island, Rocky Point and Smithsonian information, 1948 and 1980s (Legalbox 20, Folder 2)
      - South Carolina, General, 1980s-1990s approx. (Legalbox 20, Folder 3)
      - South Carolina, Isle of Palms, 1915-1990s (Legalbox 20, Folder 4)
      - South Dakota, approx 1908 and 1990s (Legalbox 20, Folder 5)
      - Tennessee, 1980s (Legalbox 20, Folder 6)
      - Texas, including Dallas, 1940s, 1980s-2000s (Legalbox 20, Folder 7-8)
      - Virginia, including Jamestown Exhibition, 1900s (Legalbox 21, Folder 2-3)
      - Washington, 1946 and 1962 (Legalbox 20, Folder 11)
      - Vermont, 1940s (Legalbox 20, Folder 10)
      - West Virginia, 1930s and 1990s (Legalbox 20, Folder 12)
      - Wisconsin,including Amato, 1899-1990s (Legalbox 20, Folder 13-14)
      - Wyoming, 1990s (Legalbox 21, Folder 4)
        Contains one article from The National Amusement Park Historical Association, "When is a Park a Park?"
    - Material Categorized by Country
      - Afhganistan, 2000s (Legalbox 25, Folder 3)
      - Australia, 1990's (Legalbox 23, Folder 2)
      - Vienna, Austria, 1980's (Legalbox 23, Folder 1)
      - Belgium, 1888, and 2002 (Legalbox 23, Folder 3)
      - Canada, 1900's (Legalbox 23, Folder 4)
      - Chile, April 11, 1953 (Legalbox 23, Folder 5)
      - China, 1880-1990 (Legalbox 23, Folder 6)
      - Denmark, 1980s (Legalbox 23, Folder 7)
      - England, 1910s-2000s (Legalbox 23, Folder 8)
      - England, Blackpool, 1980s (Legalbox 24, Folder 4)
        Blackpool Tower Circus
      - England/Europe- Ferris Wheels, 1905-2000s (Legalbox 24, Folder 2)
        This folder contains Ferris Wheel information from a variety of cultures and time periods. Most of the information is twentieth century of later, but some materials provide information on devices simmilar to Ferris Wheels in antiquity.
      - Ferris Wheel, Additional Location-Related Materials, circa 1960s-1990s (Legalbox 20, Folder 15)
      - Framer, 1880s-1990s (Legalbox 24, Folder 7)
      - Finland, Ferris Wheels, undated and 1981 (Legalbox 24, Folder 6)
      - France, Paris; Ferris Wheel, 1898-1920s (Legalbox 24, Folder 8)
      - Germany, 1890s-1990s (Legalbox 24, Folder 9)
      - Holland, 1980s (Legalbox 24, Folder 10)
      - Japan, Folder 1 (Legalbox 24, Folder 16)
      - Japan, Folder 2 (Legalbox 25, Folder 1)
      - Japan, Folder 3 (Legalbox 25, Folder 2)
      - Japan, Hong Kong, circa 1990s (Legalbox 24, Folder 11)
      - Spain, 1920s-1990s (Legalbox 24, Folder 15)
      - India, approx 1950s-2000s (Legalbox 24, Folder 12)
      - Iraq, 2001, 2007 (Legalbox 24, Folder 13)
      - Italy, 1902-1990s (Legalbox 24, Folder 14)
      - Korea, undated (Legalbox 25, Folder 7)
      - Mexico, 1990s (Legalbox 25, Folder 8)
      - New Zealand, 2000s (Legalbox 25, Folder 9)
      - Pakistan, 1964 (Legalbox 25, Folder 10)
      - Russia (Legalbox 26, Folder 1)
        The Amusement Business magazine dated August 10, 1968, contains an article on Freak Shows in North Carolina following a feature on Moscow's Gorgi Park. Also includes American Travel magazine pages from 1939 discussing travel to Moscow.
      - Scotland, Edinburgh, 1877-1950s (Legalbox 26, Folder 2)
        Most of the material in this folder ranges in date from the 1950s to the 2000s. Some of the material relates to subjects dating back to the late nineteenth-century, though most of the research was conducted in the 2000s.
      - Singapore, April 2008 (Legalbox 26, Folder 3)
      - Switzerland, undated (Legalbox 26, Folder 4)
      - Ferris Wheel, Miscellaneous Foreign Materials, 1940s-1980s (Legalbox 25, Folder 4)
  - Ferris Wheels and Amusement Rides, Miscellaneous, including some patents
    - Amusement Ride Directory, 1890s-1980s (Legalbox 22, Folder 3-4)
    - Amusement Park Ephemera, 1980s-2000s (some older materials) (Legalbox 14, Folder 3)